NANDINI CHINTA

+1 7169077993 ♦ nandinic@buffalo.edu ♦ LinkedIn ♦ GitHub

Summary

Inquisitive Artificial Intelligence graduate with software engineer experience of 2 years and proficiency in Mathematics, Statistics, Programming, and Backend development, seeking a full-time Software Engineer/ Machine Learning Engineer/ Data Scientist opportunity to work in a challenging environment that provides dynamic, responsible, and rewardable career.

Technical Skills

Languages & Database: Python, Java, MATLAB, C, JSP, JavaScript, Angular JS, MySQL, HTML, CSS, CLI, Bash Frameworks: Pytorch, Tensorflow, Keras, Scikit-learn, OpenAI Gym, Spring framework, and hibernate.

Developer Tools: Git, Visual Studio, Docker, IBM WebSphere, PyCharm, Colab, Anaconda, Jupyter, MATLAB, STS, Maven, Jenkins, Microsoft SQL

Server Management Studio, Eclipse, NetBeans, Jira

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux

Education

University at Buffalo (State University of New York)

Buffalo, NY

Masters in Artificial Intelligence | CGPA: 3.6/4.0

Aug 2021 – Dec 2022

Key Coursework: Machine learning, Pattern Recognition, Deep Learning, Reinforcement Learning, Numerical Mathematics (at the end of the second semester), Robotic Algorithms, Multi-Agent Systems

Vignan's Foundation for Science, Technology & Research (VFSTR)

Guntur, India

Bachelors in Computer Science | CGPA: 9.05/10

June 2015 - May 2019

Key Coursework: Advanced Data Structures, Database Systems, Big Data Analysis, Design & Analysis of Algorithms, Web Technologies, Operating Systems

Professional Experience

University at Buffalo, The State University of New York

February 2022 - Present

Teaching Assistant Machine Learning, Reinforcement Learning Buffalo, NY

- Conducted practical sessions for Machine Learning and Reinforcement Learning courses, and organized tutorials for 300+ students.
- Helped Professor in course structuring for the semester
- Helped students understand technical concepts: Machine Learning, Unsupervised Learning, Dimensionality Reduction, SVMs, and RL
- Designed problem sets and assignments that evaluate students' understanding of the course concepts.
- Developed a script that **auto-evaluates** students' work.

System Engineer (Python/Java Developer)

June 2019 - August 2021

Chennai, India

Tata Consultancy Services –Java, Python, Springboot, Angular,

- Developed web portal for in-house support team displaying queue data from IBM MQ eliminating manual login to each and specific server, reducing 80% of manual work.
- Added extra Knowledge Base module providing a one-stop webpage providing SOP for specific tasks, ServiceNow Groups, and application vendor details resulting in a reduction in manual search of information by **90%**.
- Developed scripts for application back-end automating manual routines and eliminating over 100 hours of manual work.
- Coordinated dashboard development with the ability to search patient records using MRN reducing manual work by 70%.
- Partnered with Kaiser to develop a web portal for medical record systems, handling data of new patients and sending to middleware using IBM MQ.
- Designed a Process Improvement using parallel processing in Java Multi-threading improving application performance by 100%.
- Developed an **ML Classification** model classifying the documents to use in certain scenarios reducing the manual work of 120+ hours at the users' end.

Software Engineer Intern

July 2018 – October 2018

Bangalore, India

TransIT mPower Globals

- Authored backend development using **JSP** to maintain website integrity, security, and efficiency.
- Prevented bugs in upcoming software releases and assist the development team in troubleshooting any issues.

Academic Projects

Fairness in Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning: Python, Pytorch, Reinforcement Learning, Deep DQN, DQN, Q-Learning

 Implemented Fairness in Multi-Agent Environment using improvised Deep Reinforcement Learning methods (Value-based and Policy gradient methods).

Treasure Hunt: Python, Pytorch, Seaborn, Reinforcement Learning, Deep Learning

• An agent is trained to acquire treasure in a stochastic custom environment using Tabular methods (Q and Double Q-Learning) and Deep RL methods (DQN and Double DQN) and visualized using matplotlib and seaborn.

NVIDIA Stock Pricing: Python, Reinforcement Learning, Q-Learning

Predicted stocks by using Q-Learning on Stock Trading Environment.

Affective State Analysis: Python, Image Processing, Object Detection, CNN, Pattern Recognition, DAISEE dataset

• Applied CNN and VGG to recognize users' engagement levels in an unstructured e-learning environment.

Diabetes Prediction: Python, Logistic Regression, Neural Networks, Pima Indians Dataset

Performed Logistic Regression and Neural Networks to predict diabetes along with regularization methods.

Morse Code Generator: C, NodeMCU, Arduino

Built a small application converting morse code into readable text format and vice versa using Node MCU.

Accomplishments

- Received Best Team Award from TCS for outstanding performance and team contributions.
- Recruited to an MNC, TCS, through a worldwide coding competition, Code Vita- 2018.

Leadership & Extra-Curricular

- Organized an inter-university-level technical event, Code Hunt involving designing programmatical quests.
- Achieved Yellow-belt in Taek-won Do
- Certified NCC (National Cadet Corps) Cadet; Achieved first place in Rifle shooting in NCC C-ATC Camp (2016)